LAUGHING MAN FANSUBS
I'm a soldier - that means I'm
Both a defendant and the judge
I am standing on both ends of the flame
Rounding curves
Overtaking life and death,
I run and fight with false shadows
No matter how many threads of
deception are woven together,
The truth shall illuminate
the face of light
Save your tears for the day
When our pain is far behind
On your feet, come with me
We are soldiers stand or die
Save your fears, take your place
Save them for the judgement day
Fast and free, follow me
Time to make the sacrifice.
We rise or fall
The refugees are now completely isolated.
All that remains is for me to observe how these
people, who are so intolerant of solitude,
will achieve the conclusion I have imagined...
Dejima, Airstrike
They won't be backing down if they only
returned fire after one of their own was shot.
We have a report from Strategic Intelligence
that all the remaining plutonium is in Dejima.
We should be ordering the mechanised
troops to advance and end this.
instead of waiting for the
inspection team to arrive.
However, we have other information
indicating that if we send
troops into Dejima, the
refugees will commit suicide
by detonating a nuclear bomb.
We can afford to wait to deploy the troops until
after we hit the refugee forces major strongholds.
Why don't we deploy those unmanned choppers?
Prime Minister Kayabuki.
You are relieved of your post as Prime Minister.
What is the meaning of this?
And the reason?
Your request for a UN inspection team,
based solely on your personal judgement, could be
construed as an act of treason during a time of crisis.
You will be kept in protective custody
until this situation is resolved.
Chief.
Who... on what authority...
What is going on?
Chief Aramaki of Section 9.
You and your men are also
suspected of abetting treason.
Please return to the office.
Hey! What are you guys...
We have been unable to make contact
with Chief Aramaki for six hours.
Is he still underground in
the Prime Minister's office?
Yes.
I see.
Then please tell him this
when you get through to him:
It's probably the result of information
manipulation by the Cabinet Intelligence Agency,
but there's a rumour circulating that the
refugees will detonate the plutonium.
There must be something else to that.
Understood.
Knowing you, though,
I'm sure you've already uncovered something.
It's the same as the other time.
The government intended to do
this from the very beginning.
Damn SDF bastards!
Just try coming into Dejima!
Put down your weapons!
Put them away right now!
Kuze!
Huh?
Don't do anything.
If you keep your weapons out of
sight, they won't attack.
He is Comrade Kuze?
They're coming!
It's out of control.
Hey!
Get some good men together.
I will reconnect everyone to my cyberbrain!
Roger!
It's the exact same thing as the joint exercise that was
conducted in the Niihama Refugee Residential Sector.
Once we enter Dejima airspace, our military
ID code will probably become invalid.
The Jigabachi will indiscriminately
attack any mechanised unit
that differ in appearance from themselves.
It can't be helped.
Bomer, hurry!
Understood.
All right, Bomer. Switch with me.
The attack's begun.
Yeah.
But it doesn't seem like we'll see any action.
There won't be a ground assault
unless the plutonium is retrieved.
Then what's that?
That has nothing to do with us.
GSDF Special Ops are secretly entering Dejima
to retrieve the nuke.
Major!
We'll enter the jamming zone soon!
Even after the comm link is cut
off, leave it open.
Keep tabs on any marine activity, too.
Roger!
The Jigabachi units are currently
circling at regular intervals.
We believe that coming in within that tall structure's
shadow, at low altitude, would be best...
The comm link's gone.
Let's go!
A unit with a different ID code is
approaching Dejima from the north.
It's disappeared into the ECM area.
ECM or Electronic Countermeasures refers
to any technique inhibiting the enemy's ability
to make use of the electromagnetic spectrum
That's it.
Follow the same course.
Roger.
The comm link is finally gone.
Yeah, I hope Batou-san's all right.
Those gloomy AIs were pretty vicious.
Yeah, true.
I'm worried.
Yeah, yeah.
It was really scary.
Oh yeah, I wonder if he was able
to catch up with Ishikawa-San.
Right.
Hey, were you able to meet up with Ishikawa-San?
As if I could get there that quickly!
I'm in physical transit on the ground!
Right. Sorry, sorry.
What about you, Ishikawa-San?
I'm also on my way.
I can't hurry too much, or I'll get caught.
How's the Major doing?
We still have her on visual feed,
so we know she's fine.
I see.
But since the Jigabachi have command of the air,
the situation is very dangerous.
We can't get in touch with the Chief, either...
It seems we have no choice
but to make our own decisions.
The refugees and Kuze;
the government and Gouda;
the Chief and the Major; and ourselves.
It seems the one who has the best standalone
strategy will determine the outcome.
Sir.
Section 4's chopper has entered Dejima.
I see.
It looks like we'll be able
to retrieve the plutonium.
Retrieving the plutonium wasn't the
real reason we deployed Section 4.
Sir, by that you mean...
You'll soon understand.
It's no good. We can't land.
There's rubble everywhere.
We don't have any choice.
We'll rappel down one by one.
Ready, Major.
Shit!
Major!
The rudder's been hit!
How is it going, Proto?
Can we reach the Tachikomas?
Yes, somehow.
I see.
That's impressive.
I wouldn't have been able to
do this if I'd been by myself.
That's not true.
You're able to act as the situation demands.
I wonder if Prime Minister Kayabuki is all right.
She is being held captive somewhere
since they will want to keep the coup from the
media until after this situation is resolved.
In order to shift responsibility
to her after the fact...
Indeed.
However, until there is a public announcement,
she still retains her powers as a Prime Minister.
There will be situations in which
her authority will prove invaluable.
That's true.
Senpai, I was able to contact the Tachikomas.
It seems the Major and the others have
entered Dejima with the plutonium.
Dejima?
I see. They've thought things through.
So, what is the situation?
It's not good.
It seems there was a scuffle
between the refugees and the SDF,
and the SDF assault choppers ran an air
raid on Dejima's military strongholds.
The chopper our people were in
was also attacked a while ago.
What?
Then, the Major and the old man...
Since there are ECM covering Dejima,
they have not been able to contact the team
to confirm their survival.
Have the Tachikomas continue to keep us informed.
Understood.
Bastard...
Batou. I'll go on ahead.
Where are you, Kuze?
Don't worry.
We still have time before
the patrol aircraft comes.
Shit.
This is bad.
We'll be surrounded by refugees.
The target is still nearby.
Get moving!
What the hell?
They followed us in?
We can't use our comm systems.
Don't use thermo-optical camouflage;
we'll risk friendly fire.
Which unit are they from?
We're in deep shit.
That's a GSDF special forces team.
We don't see Batou-San and the others.
A different chopper came to the crash
site -- I wonder what that's about.
It looks like some soldiers
offloaded, but it's hard to tell.
I can't find the Major, either.
Maybe they're using thermo-optical camouflage.
Hey, hey, what's going on?
The Aegis ships and chopper carriers that surround
Dejima began pulling back a short while ago.
The minesweepers are
deploying micro machines, too.
Let's see...
You're right...
In the event of a nuclear explosion,
you can't minimise the effects of radiation
if you don't deploy the micro
machines in advance, right?
It's the strategy where you suck the
micro machines into the affected area
by taking advantage of the backdraft
after the nuclear bomb detonates.
I still don't understand this.
Maybe it's insurance,
in case the refugees use the nukes?
No way.
It's understandable if the SDF believes
there are nuclear weapons on the island,
but according to the Major's analysis,
at least the Chief Cabinet Secretary
and Gouda know there are none, right?
Maybe it's another act, for heightened realism?
That's possible,
but even so, it's still a little too realistic.
How would you analyse the situation, Proto-kun?
What?
Let me see...
Hey, everyone.
What do you think this is?
What, what?
What?
Three hundred seventy kilometres
east of the Okinawa Atoll,
an enormous lump of iron is surfacing
just within Japan's exclusive economic zone.
Could this be...
one of the American Empire's nuclear submarines?
One of the Empire's nuclear submarines?!
I wonder what meaning is behind
its presence within our EEZ
It would mean the sub appeared due to
some action on the part of the government.
Do you mean they'd actually fire
a nuclear missile at Dejima?!
The circumstances seem to indicate
that this would be the case.
Gouda was controlling everything,
knowing this would happen
from the very beginning...
and the Chief Cabinet Secretary was accelerating
the Security Pact for the same reason?
Impossible...
It's not unreasonable.
The final acts in Gouda's scenario
would probably go along the lines of
the refugees attempting suicide with a nuclear
bomb after being surrounded by the SDF.
Both the funds generated by
Poseidon's bribery and the public
funds that disappeared from
the Ministry of Foreign Affairs
must have been used to make the
American Empire fire the nuclear missile
by those who intend to reset everything in secret.
And now, the plutonium has actually
been taken into Dejima by Section 9...
Chief, let's bring back Prime Minister Kayabuki.
As you said earlier,
she is still the Prime Minister of
Japan from a diplomatic standpoint.
Her authority may still be able
to prevent the nuclear attack.
You're right.
They never thought to search me,
even though you and Proto were.
Proto, do you know where the
Prime Minister is being held?
Okay, I'll run a search now.
Proto!
Hey, are you all right?
Damn, an offensive firewall...
Sen... pai...
Proto.
The Prime Minister's... room...
I got... the location...
Proto, you were an android?
No...
I am...
a prototype...
bioroid...
They're here!
Right.
Don't panic.
This is an infrared-guided missile.
You can hit the target with your eyes shut.
They won't be expecting any stingers.
There they are.
Fire!
Got 'em!
Enemy choppers will come this way at once.
Let's get out of here!
Kuze!
At this rate, we wouldn't be
able to make any moves, anyway.
You guys go out first.
I'll go last and bring the plutonium.
We'll meet in the building behind us.
It's a maze inside.
We can still win!
They're coming. Hurry!
Two-man teams, in two sets.
Dammit!
They're using thermo-optical camouflage!
It seems our targets aren't regular grunts.
What's going on?
According to our orders, the ones who took the
plutonium were five low-ranking soldiers...
All right, split into two groups.
We'll pursue them in formation B!
Roger!
Finding out a galaxy
of planets and stars within me.
Listening to each of them
singing the same silent melody.
I've never seen such beauty
in possibility...
No smack of doubt or fear.
(Wake up)
I hear a voice.
(And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
I see inside
(the time is right)
see the light now ever holding me.
All the truth,
(All the truth)
All I need,
to make all this reality.
(it's inside)
The beauty within the shell.
(deep within the shell)
(within the shell)
(Wake up)
I hear a voice
(And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
(the time is now)
I see inside,
see the light now ever holding me.
All the truth,
(All the truth)
all I need,
to make all this reality,
it's inside
right here within the shell.